Guide to the Lawrence Klein Papers, 1950s-2010 RL.00786
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1969-1998 and undated; 1
  - Direct Estimates of Unemployment Rate and Capacity Utilization in Macroeconometric Models, 1978 February (Box 30)
  - Can we have Parity Pricing in Agriculture?, 1978 March (Box 30)
  - Disturbances to the International Economy, 1978 Spring (Box 30)
  - Capital Requirements qnd Financial Flows for the American Economy--1978-1990, 1978 August (Box 30)
  - Econometric Models and Economic Policy, 1978 August (Box 30)
  - Capital Requirements and Financial Flows for the American Economy, 1978-1990, 1978 October (Box 30)
  - An Anatomy of Inflation, 1979 (Box 30)
  - Computers in Economics, 1979 (Box 30)
  - Econometrics, General, 1979 (Box 30)
  - Economic Models, 1979 (Box 30)
  - Council of Economic Advisers for the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, 1979 January (Box 30)
  - Capital Flows and Exchange Rates in a Multi-Regional World Model, 1979 Spring (Box 30)
  - A Decade of Research for Project LINK, 1979 June (Box 30)
  - Economic and Non-Economic Issues in Energy, 1979 July (Box 30)
  - Can we Model an LDC?, 1980 Spring (Box 30)
  - On Econometric Models, 1980 June (Box 30)
  - America's Competitive Edge, 1981 (Box 30)
  - The Significance of Budget Balance, 1981 (Box 30)
  - The Business Cycle-Hard to Supress, 1981 (Box 30)
  - A Bright Spot in an Otherwise Dull Economy, 1981 February (Box 30)
  - Alternative Paths to Econommic Stability, 1981 Summer (Box 30)
  - An Alternative to Reagonomics, 1981 October (Box 30)
  - Economic Development of ROC, 1992-1994; 4 folders (Box 30)
  - Economic Policy Formation: Theory and Implementation (Applied Econometrics in the Public Sector), undated; 2 folders (Box 31)
  - Economic Prospects for the 1980's, undated (Box 31)
  - Economic Theoretic Restrictions in Econometrics, undated; 2 folders (Box 31)
  - The Economics and Models of Eastern Europe, undated (Box 31)
  - Endogenous Treatment of Exchange Rates within the LINK System, undated (Box 31)
  - Errors in Economic Forecasting, undated (Box 31)
  - Evolution of Keynesian Economics, undated (Box 31)
  - Contains a copy of a draft version of Lawrence Klein's presentation before the FAA Forecasting Conference, undated (Box 31)
  - High Interest Rates and the Economy, undated (Box 31)
  - Impacts of Fiscal Actions on Aggregate Income: The Monetarist Controversy - The Theory and the Evidence, undated (Box 31)
  - Implications of the Electronic Computer for Economics, undated (Box 31)
  - Industrial Policy, undated (Box 31)
  - Industrial Projection and Development Models for Developing Countries, undated (Box 31)
  - Inflation: Its Causes and Possible Cures, undated (Box 31)
  - Intermediate Term Outlook of the Housing Market, undated (Box 31)
  - Introduction, undated (Box 31)
  - Issues in Econometric Studies of Investment Behavior, undated (Box 31)
  - Keynesian Economics, undated (Box 31)
  - New rules of monetary management of the Federal Reserve System, undated (Box 31)
  - Lack of Synchronization, undated (Box 31)
  - Linking Energy Models to Macroeconomic Models, undated (Box 31)
  - Forecasting and Policy Evaluation Using Large Scale Econometric Models: The State of the Art, 1969 December (Box 31)
  - The Impact of Disarmament on Aggregate Economic Activity - An Econometric Analysis, 1970 (Box 31)
  - Model Building to a Complete System of Social Accounts, 1970 June (Box 31)
  - Guidelines in Economic Stabilization: A New Considereation, 1971 (Box 31)
  - The LINK Model of World Trade with Applications to 1973-1974, 1973 March (Box 31)
  - Estimation and Prediction in Dynamic Econometric Models, 1973 October (Box 31)
  - Issues in Econometric Studies of Investment, 1973 November (Box 31)
  - The Main Economic Issues of 1974, 1973 November (Box 31)
  - Is the World Economy at the Brink?, 1974 June (Box 31)
  - Intractability of Inflation, 1974 July (Box 31)
  - The Economy - Where are we going?, 1975 June (Box 31)
  - Economic Policy Formation through the Medium of Econometric Models, 1975 August (Box 31)
  - Error Analysis of the LINK Model, 1975 October (Box 31)
  - Economic Outlook for the Nation, 1976 (Box 31)
  - The LINK Project, 1976 February (Box 31)
  - The Longevity of Economic Theory, 1976 October (Box 31)
  - Effectcs of Energy Supply-Demand Balance on the Economy, 1977 April (Box 31)
  - Economy-wide Modeling Capability with Special Reference to Energy, 1977 April (Box 31)
  - Managing the Modern Economy: Econometric Specification, 1977 April (Box 31)
  - The Economy and the Energy Impacts, 1977 August (Box 31)
  - Improving the Trade Off, 1977 November (Box 31)
  - International Economic Issues for 1978, 1977 December (Box 31)
  - Economi Policy of the Carter Administration, 1978 (Box 31)
  - Economic Prospects for the Class 78, 1978; 2 folders (Box 31)
  - Industrial Prospects for the 1980s, 1978 (Box 31)
  - US-Japan Structural Characteristics, 1978 March (Box 31)
  - The Scenario of a Worldwide Grain Shortage, 1978 August (Box 31)
  - The General Outlook, 1978 September (Box 31)
  - A Global Economic Model, 1978 September (Box 31)
  - Project LINK meetings in Athens, 1978 September (Box 31)
  - International Coordination of Economic Policies, 1979 Spring; 2 folders (Box 31)
  - The Economy of the Middle East, 1979 June (Box 31)
  - Franco-American Seminar on Macro Econometric Model Building and Application, 1979 June (Box 31)
  - Import Price Linkages in the LINK System, 1979 June (Box 31)
  - The Linkage of National and Sectoral Economic Models, 1979 July (Box 31)
  - Finnish Economic Association, 1979 August (Box 31)
  - Economic Philosophy and Industrial Policy, 1980 (Box 31)
  - Energy Prices and the World Economy, 1980 April (Box 31)
  - Macro-Econometric Modelling: A Schematic History and a View of its Possible Future, 1980 September (Box 31)
  - International Aspects of Industrial Policy, 1981 (Box 31)
  - Implementaion of Supply Side Policies, 1981 March (Box 31)
  - International Aspects of Industrial Policy, 1981 March (Box 31)
  - An Outside Look at the American Economy, 1981 March (Box 31)
  - The Importance of Being Right, 1981 May (Box 31)
  - Indian Economics and the Economy of India, 1981 summer (Box 31)
  - The Meaning of Supply Side Economics, 1981 November (Box 31)
  - Modeling the Health Sector of the Economy, undated (Box 32)
  - MODULECO, Software for Macroeconomic Modelization, undated (Box 32)
  - Optimisation (I) Dynamic Modelling and Control of National Economies, undated (Box 32)
  - Pacific Basin Econometric Research, undated (Box 32)
  - The Phillips Curve, USA, undated (Box 32)
  - Policy Recommendations, undated (Box 32)
  - The Practice of Macroeconometric Model Building and Its Rationale, undated (Box 32)
  - Production Function Estimation of Capacity Utilization, undated (Box 32)
  - A model of the world agriculture by Lawrence Klein, undated (Box 32)
  - A Quest for a More Stable Economic System, undated; 3 folders (Box 32)
  - Recent Economic Fluctuations and Stabilization Policies--An Optimal Control Approach, undated; 3 folders (Box 32)
  - The Medium Term: Models of the British Economy, undated (Box 32)
  - Regional Sub-Linkages of Economic Systems, undated (Box 32)
  - The Role of War in the Maintenance of American Economic Prosperity, undated (Box 32)
  - Introduction to the NBER/NSF Model Comparison Seminar: An Analysis of Results, 1974 March (Box 32)
  - Notes on Testing the Predictive Performance of Econometric Models, 1974 March (Box 32)
  - Opening Address, 1974 June (Box 32)
  - The Next Generation of Macro Models, 1974 October (Box 32)
  - The Next Cycle, 1975 June (Box 32)
  - Outlook for the World Economy, 1976 February (Box 32)
  - Political Aspects of Economic Control, 1977 January (Box 32)
  - Potentials of Econometrics for Commodity Stabilization Policy Analysis, 1977 March (Box 32)
  - New Directions for Aggregative Economic Policy, 1977 March (Box 32)
  - New Directions for Aggregative Economic Policy, 1977 March (Box 32)
  - The Outlook for the Major Industrial Countries, 1977 May (Box 32)
  - Money in a General Equilibrium System: Empirical Aspects of the Quantity Theory, 1977 September (Box 32)
  - Production Function Estimation of Capacity Utilization, 1977 November (Box 32)
  - Oil and the World Economy, 1977 December (Box 32)
  - Project LINK: Policy Applications and Implications for the World Economy, 1978 (Box 32)
  - Protectionism. An Analysis from Project LINK, 1978 February; 2 folders (Box 32)
  - Overview of the Economy, 1978 April (Box 32)
  - Protectionism. Some Further Results from LINK, 1978 October (Box 32)
  - Scale of Macro -Econometric Models and Accuracy of Forecasting, 1978 October; 2 folders (Box 32)
  - Overall Outlook, 1978-1979 (Box 32)
  - Modular Composition of the Proposed Study of Productivity and Capital Formation, 1979 Spring (Box 32)
  - A Single Year's Effect on the Proposed Study of Capital Formation and Productivity, 1979 Spring (Box 32)
  - New Delhi Conference, 1979 November (Box 32)
  - Money Supply Hard Control, 1980 Spring (Box 32)
  - Outlook for the Developing Countries and World Financial Markets, and Managing Country Risk, 1980 Spring (Box 32)
  - Some Economic Scenarios for the 1980's, 1980 Winter (Box 32)
  - NOVA SPES, 1980 December (Box 32)
  - Project LINK Volume, 1996-1998; 2 folders (Box 32)
  - Scope and Limitations of Macroeconometric Model Building, undated (Box 32)
  - Some Dilemmas of Monetary Policy, undated (Box 33)
  - Some Observations on the World Business Cycle, undated (Box 33)
  - Some Thoughts on Contemporary Econometrics and Its Present Tendencies, undated (Box 33)
  - The Structure of U.S. Foreign Trade and Payments, undated (Box 33)
  - Supply Side Modelling, undated (Box 33)
  - Tax Policies and Economic Expansion in the U.S., undated (Box 33)
  - Trends in the Economies of the U.S. and U.S.S.R., undated (Box 33)
  - Trends in the U.S. Economy and the Future of U.S.-Japanese Economic Relations, undated (Box 33)
  - Use of Econometric Models in the Policy Process, undated (Box 33)
  - On the Uses of Macroeconometric Models, undated (Box 33)
  - The Wharton Quarterly Model of the US Economy, undated (Box 33)
  - The World Economy in the Decade of the 1980's, undated; 3 folders (Box 33)
  - World Trade Forecasts: Retrospect and Prospect, undated (Box 33)
  - The Forecasting Performance in the 1970s, Various Dates (Box 33)
  - Forecasting Performance of Models, Various Dates (Box 33)
  - Comparison of the Forecasting Performance of WEFA to ARIMA Times Series Methods, Various Dates (Box 33)
  - How to Evaluate the Forecasting Performance of a Macroeconomic Model, Various Dates (Box 33)
  - The Theory of the Multiplier and the Business Cycle, and Economic Consequences of the ADL Capital Needs Program, 1974 August (Box 33)
  - Tax Cut: Why it Must be Quick and Big, 1975 February (Box 33)
  - Simultaneous Equations Estimation, 1976 January (Box 33)
  - Statement for the Committee on Banking, Currency and Housing of the House of Representatives, 1976 July (Box 33)
  - Statistical Needs for Economic Analysis: A User's Viewpoint, 1976 August (Box 33)
  - Simulated Reality - A Contradiction in Terms?, 1976 October (Box 33)
  - Financing the Energy Program, 1977 (Box 33)
  - Reply to Clopper Almon's 'Comments on Trade Impact Studies Using the Wharton Annual and Industry Forecasting Model', 1977 January (Box 33)
  - President Ford's Economic Report, 1977 February (Box 33)
  - Testimony before the Senate Foreing Relations Committee, Sub-Committee on Foreing Economic Policy, 1977 March (Box 33)
  - Understanding Inflation, 1977 June (Box 33)
  - The World Business Cycle Today, 1977 June (Box 33)
  - The Supply Side, 1977 July; 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Waiting for the Revival of Capital Formation, 1977 August (Box 33)
  - The State of the Economy and Fiscal Policy, 1978 January (Box 33)
  - Testimony on The Revised Version of the Full Employment And Balanced Growth Act of 1977, 1978 February (Box 33)
  - Simulated Protectionism According to Project LINK, 1978 March (Box 33)
  - Economic Prospects, 1978 March (Box 33)
  - A Review of U.S.-Japan Structural Characteristics, 1978 June (Box 33)
  - The Summary from the Text Of Declaration at the Bonn Summit, 1978 August (Box 33)
  - What America asks of Japan, 1978 September (Box 33)
  - Scale of Macro-Econometric Models and Accuracy of Forecasting, 1978 October; 2 folders (Box 33)
  - U.S. Economic Policy and the Outlook for the World Economy, 1978 December (Box 33)
  - Statement before the Committee on the Budget of the United States House of Representatives, 1979 February (Box 33)
  - The United States-Japan Economic Relationship in the Context of the World Economy, 1979 March (Box 33)
  - The Stability of the Dollar and the Future of the World Monetary System, 1979 Spring (Box 33)
  - Will Inflation Ever Come Down?, 1979 May (Box 33)
  - The State of the Economy and Directions for Economic Policy, 1979 July (Box 33)
  - Subnational Models, 1979 July (Box 33)
  - The World Economic Outlook, 1979 August; 6 folders (Box 33)
  - World Summary Tables for Oil, 1980 March (Box 33)
  - Persian Gulf Oil Scenario, 1980 April (Box 33)
  - What Kind of Recession, Mild or Severe?, 1980 Spring (Box 33)
  - Statement before the Senate Finance Committee Hearing, 1980 July; 2 folders (Box 33)
  - A Worsening Inflation Outlook, 1980 November (Box 33)
  - Supply and Demand Side Economics, 1981 (Box 33)
  - USA/Japan Perspectives, 1981 (Box 33)
  - World Economic Issues, 1981 January (Box 33)
  - The Theory of Supply and Demand Side Economics, 1981 March (Box 33)
  - Two Decades of U.S. Economic Policy and Present Prospects: A View from Outside, 1981 September (Box 33)
  - Evaluating Data Needs Relevant to the Use of Unemployment in Labor Market Macro Models, undated (Box 33)
  - International Research Cooperation, undated (Box 34)
  - LINK and the Other World Economic Model Projects: A Clarifying Statement, undated (Box 34)
  - Simulation of the LINK System under Alternative Exchange Rate Policies of Common Market Countries, undated (Box 34)
  - Scope and Limitations of Macroeconometric Model Building, 1978 August (Box 34)
  - Oil Prices and the World Economy, 1980 November (Box 34)
  - Model Specification and Estimation, 1981 (Box 34)
  - Selected Writings' permissions, 1996 (Box 34)
- Writings by Others, 1970-1992 and undated; 2
  - Capital Requirements and Financial Flows for the American Economy, 1978-1990, undated (Box 34)
  - Dynamic Linear Programming, undated (Box 34)
  - Dynamics and Structure of Fixed Capital Stock in the USSR: New Approaches, undated (Box 34)
  - An Econometric Analysis of the Steel Industry in the United States, 1950-1970, undated (Box 34)
  - The Financing of Public Expenditure, undated (Box 34)
  - Higher Oil Prices and the Western European Economies: An Appraisal of Adjustment Policies, undated (Box 34)
  - On New Uses of Dynamic Input-Output Macroeconomic Models, undated (Box 34)
  - Editorial comments and papers, undated (Box 34)
  - AEA and Association of Economic Scientific Institutions of the Russian Academy of Sciences, undated (Box 34)
  - The Economic Outlook for 1971, 1970 November (Box 34)
  - Monetary Interdependence among Industrial Countries: A Study of Interest Rate Linkages, 1974 June (Box 34)
  - Household Flow-of-Funds Equations: Specification and Estimation, 1974 August (Box 34)
  - Econometric Analysis of a Regional System I: A Forecasting Model, 1974 September (Box 34)
  - Optimal Control of a Noisy Economy with the UK as an Example, 1975 (Box 34)
  - Introduction to the Working Papers on Community Development, 1975 January (Box 34)
  - The Impact of Pollution Standards on Shortages, Inflation, Real Income and Unemployment Based on Analysis of The Paper Industry and All Manufactoring, 1975 March (Box 34)
  - The Structure of Simultaneous Equations Estimators, 1975 March (Box 34)
  - A Monthly Integrated/National Econometric Model for Regional Policy Planing, 1975 April; 2 folders (Box 34)
  - ETA: A Model for Energy Technology Assessment, 1975 December (Box 34)
  - On the Application of Optimal Control To Large Scale Econometric Models, 1976 October (Box 34)
  - Updated World Trade Matrices, 1971-1975, and an Analysis of Recent Changes in Trade Patterns, 1977 August (Box 34)
  - The Estimation of Supply Response in Australian Agriculture: The CRESH/CRETH Production System, 1978 May (Box 34)
  - Wharton Annual and Industry Forecasting Model, 1978 July (Box 34)
  - An Evaluation of the Forecasting Performance of Macro Economic Models, with Special Emphasis on Size, 1978 October (Box 34)
  - Financial Transfers from Developed Regions to Developing Regions, 1978 October (Box 34)
  - Notes on an Econometric Model of China, 1979 June (Box 34)
  - Modeling Analysis for Retirement Income Policy: Background and Overview, 1980 (Box 34)
  - Models of the Socialist Economy, 1981; 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Annex B, 1991 (Box 34)
  - The Measurement of Wealth in the United States, 1992 March (Box 34)
  - Russian Economy in Transition: Computer Simulation of Capital Stock Prices, 1992 March (Box 34)
- Miscellaneous, 1972-2000 and undated; 3
  - Andras Simon, 1974-1976 (Box 34)
  - Correspondence with Y. K. Chian (World Scientific Publishing Co), Jonathan Eaton, Otto Eckstein, Peter Pauly, and Robert W. Rashe among others, 1972, 1992, 1994, 1995 (Box 34)
  - Equipment purchases, 2000 (Box 34)
  - Nominees for the Prize Rey Jaime I of Spain, 1993 (Box 34)
  - Economic outlook meeting, 1979; 3 folders (Box 34)
  - Quarterly US data on sources and uses of funds for the period 1952-1954, undated; 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Unsorted miscellaneous, undated (Box 34)
- Audio tapes, Project LINK, 1969, 10 items; 1 box, 10 1/4-inch open-reel audio tapes
  Includes 10 1/4-inch open reel audio tapes of the first worldwide Project LINK conference in Hakone, Japan, in 1969. Use of the recordings requires production of listening copies. Please contact Research Services before coming to use this collection.
  - LINK No. 1. Side 1: Welcome speech by S. Okita, general introduction by T. Watanabe; Session I, Presentation by R. Rhomberg, comment by B.G. Hickman. Side 2: Session II. Comment by Hickman (continued); general discussion., 1969 September 16 (Box 35)
    - 1/4-inch open-reel audio tape original. (Box 35, Audio-reel RL00786-RR-0001)
  - LINK No. 2. Side 1: Session II. RR Rhomberg (Remains), comment by Verdoorn; Session III. Waelbroek's presentation; Side 2: Session III. Discussion; Session IV. Presentation by Marin Curtond, comment by S. Ichimura, 1969 September 16
    - 1/4-inch open-reel audio tape original. (Box 35, Audio-reel RL00786-RR-0002)
  - Link No. 3. Side 1: Session IV. Marin-Curtond (Remains); Sept. 17, Session I. Klein, organization of P. Link. Side 2: Session II. Klein, Conceptual Basis of Model (cointinued); An Experiment in International Linkage by Helliwell., 1969 September 16-17
    - 1/4-inch open-reel audio tape original. (Box 35, Audio-reel RL00786-RR-0003)
  - LINK No. 4. Side 1: The Price Variables in International Trade Equations, by Kravis. Side 2: Presentation by G.B. Taplin, comment by James Ball., 1969 September 17
    - 1/4-inch open-reel audio tape original. (Box 35, Audio-reel RL00786-RR-0004)
  - LINK No. 5, Side 1. Session I (chairman: Jacobsson), Presentation by Ball, comment by Gordon. Side 2: Session II (chairman: Jacobsson), International Comparison of Existing Models by Morigachi, comments by Klein., 1969 September 18
    - 1/4-inch open-reel audio tape original. (Box 35, Audio-reel RL00786-RR-0005)
  - LINK No. 6, Side 1: Session II (chairman: Jacobsson), presented by Morigachi (continued from No. 5). Side 2: Sept. 19, Friday, Session I (chairman: Ball), presented by Klein, comment by Taplin., 1969 September 18-19
    - 1/4-inch open-reel audio tape original. (Box 35, Audio-reel RL00786-RR-0006)
  - LINK No. 7, Side 1: Session I, L.R. Klein's paper, comment by Takemoto; Session II, Krelle's paper, comments by T. Watanabe. Side 2: Session II, open discussion on Krelle's paper (continued)., 1969 September 19
    - 1/4-inch open-reel audio tape original. (Box 35, Audio-reel RL00786-RR-0007)
  - LINK No. 8, Side 1: Open discussion on improving national models. Side 2: Open discussion on improving national models (continued)., 1969 September 19
    - 1/4-inch open-reel audio tape original. (Box 35, Audio-reel RL00786-RR-0008)
  - LINK No. 9, Side 1: Session I, chairman Gordon. Side 2: Session II, discussion led by Gordon., 1969 September 20
    - 1/4-inch open-reel audio tape original. (Box 35, Audio-reel RL00786-RR-0009)
  - LINK No. 10, Side 1: Session II, discussion led by Gordon (continued)., 1969 September 20
    - 1/4-inch open-reel audio tape original. (Box 35, Audio-reel RL00786-RR-0010)